原创翻译  双语字幕
《超女》前情提要
Previously on Supergirl...
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译     DustD  洗七里  DerbyNinja
你拿他和无数人的生命冒险
You risked his life and the lives of countless others
只为了逼我去测试哈伦·艾尔
just so I would be forced to test the Harun-El.
翻译     阿p  左左  C·A
所以你需要一个由头
So you needed a nudge,
和一只小白鼠
and a test dummy.
奏效了  詹姆斯会活下来
Well, it worked. James is gonna live,
校对     肉松  饿得慌
而你会腐烂
and you're gonna rot.
因为我绝不会给你解药
'Cause I will never give you the cure.
十分钟前我让人给了我解药
I had someone give me the cure ten minutes ago.
时间轴    想念Gallifrey的Wholock  三水
后期     你是不是饿得慌
伊芙
Eve.
-多久了  -从头到尾
- How long? - Forever.
待在这里  看着她
Stay here and take care of her.
总监     你是不是饿得慌
超女  很高兴终于与你见面了
Supergirl. Nice to finally meet you.
你有超能力?
You have powers?
我有超能力
I have powers.
你之前表现不错
You had a good run,
但这一次
but this time,
地球要回击了
the planet hits back.
你是怎么做到的
How are you doing this?
你觉得我是怎么做到的
How do you think I did it?
我可是莱克斯·卢瑟
I'm Lex Luthor.
三年前
抬起你的右手
Raise your right hand.
你发誓会说实话  全部的实话
Do you swear to tell the truth, the whole truth,
而且只说实话吗
and nothing but the truth?
我发誓
I do.
一旦不赞同他的痴迷
One disagreement over his obsession
他就隔离了我
and he shut me out.
把我驱逐出公司  专注于他的改革
Threw me out of the company and himself into his crusade.
他杀过人
He killed people.
卢瑟一直想请超人在他的组织中担任职位
Luthor kept offering Superman a place in his organization.
当然  超人知道他是谁
Of course, Superman knew who he was.
卢瑟不喜欢被回绝
And Luthor didn't take the rejection well.
他常说我们"为优秀所累"
He used to say we were "burdened with excellence,"
只有我和他一起对抗世界
and it was just me and him against the world.
说句实话  我相信他
And if I'm honest with myself, I believed him.
我盲目地相信他想要搭档
I was blind enough to think that he wanted a partner...
但是他想要的是氪星宠物
But he wanted a pet Kryptonian.
他想要的是谄媚者
...but he wanted a sycophant.
他绑架了我
He kidnapped me.
我有折磨留下来的十六道伤痕
And I have 16 scars from the torture.
我将我们所有的通信都提交为证物
I have submitted our every correspondence into evidence.
里面证据众多
Enough smoking guns for an army.
另外
Plus,
当他将太阳变红时
when he turned the sun red,
我戴着窃听器
I was wearing a wire.
卢瑟先生  你被控谋杀
Mr. Luthor, you are charged with murder,
生态恐怖主义  以及反人类罪
ecoterrorism, and crimes against humanity.
鉴于你选择为自己辩护
Since you have chosen to represent yourself,
在我宣读判决结果前
have you anything to say
你有什么要说的吗
before I render the verdict of this court?
是超人逼我做的
Superman made me do it.
这是范式转移
This is a paradigm shift.
外星人在我们之中
Aliens are among us.
而在人类将来的历史中
And for the rest of human history,
只会存在"超人之前"
there will only ever be "before Superman"
和"超人之后"
and "after."
我在预防人类遭遇灭绝
I am protecting mankind from an extinction event.
但如果这支反应过度的...
And if this pearl-clutching jury of my...
人类陪审团
peers
想因此把我送进监狱
wants to put me behind bars for it,
欢迎他们试试看
they are welcome to try.
但请记住
But know this.
我总会想方设法改变最终的结果
I will always have my thumb on the scales.
亚历山大·约瑟夫·卢瑟
Alexander Joseph Luthor,
你所有的罪行被判有罪
you've been found guilty on all counts
将服刑连续三十一个...
and will serve 31 consecutive
无期徒刑
life sentences.
也许我们该判三十二个
Maybe we should make it 32.
卢瑟先生  抱歉  抱歉
Mr. Luthor! Sorry. Sorry.
卢瑟先生  卢瑟先生
Mr. Luthor! Mr. Luthor!
你这间牢房不错
Nice prison you got here.
这是用于配偶探视的
It's for conjugal visits.
在这之后  就回到水泥与铁杆之后了
But still, after this, it's back to concrete and iron.
听起来很寂寞
Sounds lonely.
斯特赖克是个培养皿
Stryker's is a Petri dish.
渣滓之城
Bottle city.
我设法教了一些牢友下棋
I've even managed to teach some of the inmates chess.
我喜欢指导别人
I like mentoring.
真是浪费
It's a waste.
你拥有千载难逢的大脑
You're a once-in-a-generation mind
并且是唯一站出来
and the only man standing
阻止人类彻底毁灭的人
between us and total annihilation.
我曾经给你写过许多信
You know, I used to write you letters.
我都读了
I read them.
对于一个喜欢曼森的女孩来说  你文笔不错
You're literate for a Manson girl.
你不是曼森
You are not Manson.
而且说实话  我不是普通女孩
And for the record, I'm not just some girl.
我有耶鲁大学的文学与物理学位
I've got degrees from Yale in literature and physics,
并且是前少女组北卡罗来纳州小姐
and I am a former Junior Miss North Carolina.
我不需要你的简历
I don't need your resume.
虽然
Although
我或许知道有谁需要
I may know someone who does.
-泰斯马克女士  -伊芙
- Ms. Tessmacher-- - Eve.
泰斯马克女士
Ms. Tessmacher,
我需要你帮我一个忙
I need you to do me a favor.
你了解凯特科杂志吗
What do you know about CatCo magazine?
他们的发行量减少了
Their circulation's down?
吉米·奥尔森在那里工作  他一直是我的眼中刺
Jimmy Olsen works there. He's been a thorn.
但是他与第二位氪星人有关系
But he's connected to the second Kryptonian.
而我正巧知道凯特·格兰特
And I happen to know that Cat Grant
需要一名新助理
needs a new assistant.
像你这样有才华的女人
A woman of your talents
在那里找到工作肯定不难
would have no problem finding a job there.
交给我吧
Consider it done.
但你知道我能做的事还有很多
But you do know there's a lot more that I can do--
你会有机会的
And you will.
我们将会让你变得无法抗拒
We're gonna make you undeniable.
六个月前
典狱长
Warden.
你丈夫喜欢国王队的票吗
Did your husband enjoy those Knights tickets?
当然  边场票
Oh, yes. Courtside?
他感觉就像是尼科尔森
He felt like Nicholson.
而且  其他的囚犯
And, uh, the other inmates,
他们似乎很喜欢你运来的那些龙虾
they seemed to like all that lobster you trucked in.
龙虾是十八世纪农民的食物
Lobster's 18th century peasant food,
只适合签卖身契的人和被监禁的人
only fit for the indentured and the incarcerated.
我不知道你还会创作艺术品
I, uh, didn't know you did artwork.
不过是几何学
It's just geometry.
《汉尼拔翻越阿尔卑斯山》
Hannibal Crossing the Alps.
这幅画表达了什么
So, what's it, like, represent?
无聊  找我有事吗  典狱官
Boredom. Can I help you, Warden?
抱歉
Sorry.
卡兹尼亚大使馆来电话找你
You have a call from the Kaznian Embassy.
部长  好久不见
你说过有特殊情况就给你打电话
又发现一个氪星人
她和超女一模一样
她失忆了
你确定吗
是的  卢瑟先生
她有超能力吗
有超能力
尽快赶来
好
典狱官  我得离开72小时
Warden, I'm going to need to leave for 72 hours.
什么  你不能
What? You can't just--
你母亲还住在枫叶大道245号  对吗
Your mother still lives at 245 Maple Drive, right?
每周五晚都去圣约瑟夫玩宾果
Bingo night every Friday at St. Joseph's?
你总不希望那个叫贝蒂·拜罗姆的婆娘
We wouldn't want that awful Betty Byrom woman
终于有机会大胜而归
to finally have a chance at winning.
对吧
Would we?
72小时
Seventy-two hours.
你打算怎样出去
How are you gonna leave without--
这交给我
Leave that to me.
我需要我的财物和一位裁缝
I'll need my effects and my tailor.
还有我的私人飞机
And my jet.
车移至E8
Rook to E-8.
皇后移至H5
Queen to H-5.
象移至G6
Bishop to G-6.
皇后移至H8
Queen to H-8.
将军
Checkmate.
卡兹尼亚
你好
超 女
第四季 第十六集
卡兹尼亚
九个月前
等等
你  别乱来
她很危险
她不过是个姑娘
看看她
不过是迷路的流浪狗
瞧
你是谁
真神奇  你和她一模一样
我们确认过超女的行踪了吗
在美国
America.
艾丽克斯
Alex.
艾丽克斯是谁
你会乖乖听话
成为有力的武器  对吗
我想是的
艾丽克斯
Alex.
卡兹尼亚
Kaznia.
父亲  母亲
服从
听
很好
现在我们带你去看看外面
太阳给你能力
雪鸟
听
控制住她  控制住她
艾丽克斯  艾丽克斯
Alex... Alex...
她和超女一模一样
你确定吗
是的  卢瑟先生
她有超能力吗
有超能力
尽快赶来
你能立刻赶来吗
救命
别怕
谁来救救我
死了三个人
我的人不敢进去
你好
他不必害怕
He has nothing to fear,
你也是
and neither do you.
我叫莱克斯
My name is Lex.
艾丽克斯
Alex?
是啊
Sure.
艾丽克斯
Alex.
我可以教她如何控制能力
I can show her how to master her powers
并帮你控制住她
and help you contain her.
我就知道你能做到
I know you're the man for the job.
莱克斯·卢瑟
Lex Luthor.
关于氪星的一切你就是头号专家
Foremost specialist on everything Krypton.
你会让她成为卡兹尼亚的武器  对吗
You will make her Kaznia's weapon, hmm?
你让她恨谁她就恨谁
She'll hate whomever you want.
操作性条件反射是我的专长
Operant conditioning is a specialty of mine.
但是你必须严格按照我的指示去做
But you'll need to follow my instructions to the letter.
我们无法击垮氪星人  但或许可以操控她
Can't break a Kryptonian, but maybe we can bend one.
你要什么回报
And for this?
钱  和之前说好的一样
Money, as discussed.
他手头没以前那么富裕了
He's not as liquid as he used to be.
我警告你  你不过是个顾问
I warn you, you are only a consultant.
我发誓
Cross my heart.
就是他害她十分紧张
That's the one who made her uncomfortable.
让他消失
Get rid of him.
我会把他调到基地的其他地方去
I will reassign him elsewhere on the base.
她不会再见到他了
She will not see him again.
她有透视能力
She can see through walls.
彼得
Pyotr.
下次不要畏缩
Next time, don't flinch.
我也在这种地方住过许久
你喜欢这里吗
我不知道我喜欢什么
他们教你英语了吗
Did they teach you any English?
教了一点
Little.
你在
Are you
生我的气吗
angry at me?
因为你救了一个孩子吗  没有
For saving a child? No.
你做得对
You did the right thing.
我听到了哀痛声
I heard pain.
我并不知道自己的能力
I did not know my strength.
你想知道吗
Would you like to?
艾丽克斯
Alex,
我唯一记得的只有你的名字
your name is only thing I remember.
这么说吧  我们以前是好友
Let's just say we were besties.
朋友
好朋友
我是哪里人
我和别人不一样
为什么
我很快会把所有的事都告诉你的
I'll tell you everything soon.
时间到了  我要走了
Time's up and I have to go.
巧克力饼干
吃吧
Go on.
你要用他们的方式去看待这个世界
You need to see the world as they do.
我会寄些书给你
给你一些学习的资料
在我回来的时候
要说英文
English.
真是天上掉馅饼  怎么会这样  克隆人吗
Pennies from heaven. How does this happen? Clone?
我想我知道原因
I think I know.
那叫做哈伦·艾尔  是黑氪石
It's called Harun-El. Black Kryptonite.
它把氪星劈成两半
It splits Kryptonians in two.
超女一定是接触到它了
Supergirl must have come into contact with it.
她现在脑子一片空白
She's a blank slate.
没有超女的记忆
Doesn't share Supergirl's memories.
我们还不知道黑氪石究竟是怎么回事
We don't know exactly how this works, yet.
我们
"We"?
是莉娜  她手上还有更多的石头
It's Lena, and she has more.
好极了
Brava.
我和你说了我在L公司比在凯特科更有作为
I told you I'd be more useful at L-Corp than CatCo.
我亲爱的妹妹怎么样了
And how is my darling sister?
执着于此
Obsessed.
她就快利用哈尔·艾尔实现突破了
About to have a breakthrough with the Harun-El.
但她暂时还没有结果
But she hasn't produced results yet.
确保她会取得成果
See that she does.
我是留在这里和共产党一起吗
So do I stay and hang with the commies?
什么  不  你要开车
What? No, you're driving.
好的
Oh, sure.
有什么计划
So what's the play?
纸老虎
Paper tigers.
中文的成语
Chinese idiom.
纸老虎有威胁  但也不堪一击
Paper tigers threaten, but are destroyed easily.
卡兹尼亚想对美国采取行动
Kaznia wants to move on the US.
他们比俄罗斯人还疯狂
They're crazier than Russia.
他们想恢复苏联往昔的辉煌岁月
They wanna bring back the glory days of the Soviet Union.
所以你要帮他们吗
So you wanna help them?
我不在乎他们的政治
I don't care about their politics.
改朝换代  国王驾崩
Regimes change. Kings die.
但如果卡兹尼亚袭击美国
But if Kaznia attacks America,
我阻止了袭击  美国就会把我当英雄来膜拜
and I foil the attack, America will hail me as a hero.
所以在东西方两地  我都需要安排罪羊者
To do that, I'm gonna need patsies in both the East and the West.
奥蒂斯  去找你姐姐
So, Otis, fetch your sister
给我找个真正的美国人
and find me a real American.
找一个有感召力又激进的人
Someone charismatic, a radical.
我正好有个人选  卢瑟先生
I think I know just the guy, Mr. Luthor.
他叫本·洛克伍德  样子看着很聪明
Name's Ben Lockwood, seems smart.
很高兴有聪明人
I'm glad someone does.
新移民
本·洛克伍德
不是文化的问题
这是生物学的问题
等等  要去哪
Wait. Where are you going?
回斯特赖克岛
Back to Stryker's.
监狱是世上最好的不在场证明
Prison's the best alibi the world has yet devised,
而我将需要大量的不在场证明
and I'm about to need a lot of alibis.
今天美国约塞米蒂号军舰驶近了卡兹尼亚海
The USS Yosemite moved closer to the Kaznian Sea today,
给本已动荡不安的海域施加了压力
placing pressure on an already volatile area.
对于两周前贝克总统在马斯丁总统
Critics of President Baker, who took office two weeks ago
提出辞职后上任
after President Marsdin's resignation,
其批评者对此决定提出质疑
are questioning his decisions...
艾丽克斯寄
卡兹尼亚
《查拉图斯特拉如是说》
弗里德里希·尼采  著
《普通语言学教程》
索绪尔  著
《罗马帝国衰亡史》
爱德华·吉本  著
《凝望上帝》
《政治经济学批判》
卡尔·马克思  著
艾丽克斯
Alex.
我小的时候
When I was a boy,
跟一位国际象棋大师阿纳托利·卡尔波夫
I learned this game from a grand master,
学会了下国际象棋
Anatoly Karpov.
我就是这样学会说俄语的
That's how I learned to speak your language.
看来该教教你学说我的语言了
Seems fitting that it should teach you mine.
你的书已经教会我了
I think your books handled that.
是吗  那好
Have they? Okay.
腓力二世
Philip of Macedon.
从公元前359开始统治  直至遭人暗杀
Ruled from 359 BC until his assassination.
是亚历山大大帝之父  与你同名之人
Father of Alexander the Great, your namesake.
腓力的权利基础并不大  他想建立一个帝国
Philip had a small power base. He wanted to build an empire.
但是到最后  人都只有一生的时间
But, in the end, we only have one lifetime.
亚历山大继承了他父亲的伟业
Alexander inherits his father's work,
但他的成就是腓力一辈子做梦也想不到的
but he does more than Philip ever could have dreamed.
他征服了世界
He conquers the world.
你对此很感兴趣吗
This appeals to you?
你的语气和我妹妹很像
You sound like my sister.
莉娜
Lena.
是的
Yes.
你有专心听我说话
You pay attention.
有时你让我想起了她
You remind me of her sometimes.
以前我觉得我们形影不离
I used to think we were inseparable.
我们会改变一切
That we were going to change everything.
然后呢
What happened?
人们总是让人失望
People disappoint.
但是还不错
Not bad, though.
你看那本书的次数比其他的书多
You've read that one more than the others.
《了不起的盖茨比》   为什么
Gatsby. Why?
书写得非常好
It's beautiful.
内容丰富
Lush.
我
I, uh...
我想应该是这个词吧
I think that's the word.
当中的语言文字
The language...
很难像那样去想象这个世界
It's hard to even imagine the world that way.
我让你看  不是因为语言文字优美
I didn't give it to you because it's pretty.
这本书讲的是一群既平庸又败家的傻子
This is a book about vapid, profligate fools.
拿钱总是需要别人的牺牲
Money is always acquired at someone else's expense.
但是你有钱
But you have money.
你肯定有  你来来去去的
You must. The way you come and go--
没错
I do.
因为这是他们的武器
Because it is their weapon.
他们的世界就是这么运作的
The way their world works.
你再读一遍
Read it again.
谢谢  米凯尔
Thank you, Mikhail.
你妈妈
Your mother.
她...
She's...
在工作吗
She's working?
是的
Yes.
难为你经常一个人在家
I'm sorry you have to be alone so much.
我会常来的
I'll try to visit more.
她救了你们的那晚
The night she saved you,
为什么那些男的要袭击你们
why were those men attacking?
他们是小偷
They were thieves.
又只有我和妈妈两个人
It is just me and my mother.
为什么
Why?
我爸爸是个坏人
My father was a bad man.
他离开我们了
He left us.
我爸爸也是坏人
I had a bad father, too.
你爸爸干了什么
What did yours do?
他留下了
He stayed.
我以前也祈祷 希望有个救我的英雄
I used to pray for a hero like the one you got.
很久都没有等到
Took a long time,
但现在你来了
but here you are.
该走了
Time to go.
对不起 米凯尔
Sorry, Mikhail.
我不明白  为什么我们要这么着急
I don't understand. Why we are in such a hurry?
那是什么
What is that?
我们得带你进去
We got to get you inside.
我怎么回事
What is happening to me?
地球上只有一种东西
There's only one thing on this Earth
能伤害你
that can hurt you,
美国人就在天上洒满了这东西
and the Americans just seeded the skies with it.
好疼
你不会再有这种感觉了
You will never feel like this again.
我会保护你
I will protect you.
但我们先要做另一件事
But there's something we have to do first.
你的身体很虚弱
Your flesh is weak.
这个我们只能做一次
It's the only time we can do this.
有一天
Someday,
你可能得和她对战
you may have to match her.
谁
Who?
是时候让你知道真相了
It's time for you to know your full truth.
你很强壮
You are strong.
你是卡兹尼亚人
You are Kaznia.
但你还有别的身份
But you are also something more.
你看到的绿色闪电
That green flash you saw,
对你们种族有毒
it's poison to your species.
是由你母星的碎片构成的
Made of fragments of your home planet.
你是氪星最后的血脉之一
You are one of the last daughters of Krypton.
氪星
Krypton?
你会将世界推向和平的新时代
You will usher in a new era of peace.
平等
Equality.
不像卡兹尼亚那样信奉贪心的国家
Nations unlike Kaznia who believe in greed
会联合起来反抗你
will rise against you.
其中最强的战士
And its greatest champion
会阻碍你和你的事业
will stand between you and your work.
空气里的氪石
已经除去了
我现在能恢复训练了吗
我说过了  你要说英文
I told you, English.
你不要把口音露出来
You need to keep your accent.
为什么
Why?
你想让我去美国
You want me to go to America.
总会有那一天  你现在还没准备好
Someday. You're not ready yet.
我准备好了
Yes, I am!
我想亲眼看看
I want to see it.
我想知道更多
I want to know more.
这个超女是什么人
Who is this Supergirl
跟我有关吗
to me?
为什么她长得像我
Why does she look like me?
简单来说
Put simply,
她是你妹妹
your sister.
她霸占了你在世界上的地位
She has usurped your position in the world.
那是她抢走的
Taken from you.
就像你的莉娜
Like your Lena.
对
Yes.
或许你确实应该多去看看
Maybe you should see more.
四个月前
纳欣诺市
National City.
你知道卡兹尼亚  氪星
You know Kaznia, Krypton.
现在你要感受一下巴比伦
Now you need to experience Babylon.
你好
Hey!
小姐
Kid!
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
琳达
Linda.
琳达·李
Linda Lee.
Well, Linda Lee,
你能再给我们拿些这个吗
why don't you go on and get us some more of this?
没问题
Of course.
你看见什么了
What did you see?
一个猪饲料槽
A pig trough.
其中一个人别着
One of the men had a pin
艾美特克标志  他们是制造武器的
with the AmerTek insignia. They make weapons.
美国的出口  电影
America's exports, movies
炸弹
and bombs.
美国人为了生活幸福让卡兹尼亚受苦
Kaznia suffers so that Americans can live like this.
超女就维护那些人吗
And Supergirl defends those men?
对  因为她
Yes, because she's
心肠太软
soft.
习惯了这种生活方式
Accustomed to a certain lifestyle.
你想了解她吗
You wanna understand her?
就是这里  这是超女住的地方
This is the place. This is where Supergirl lives.
或者叫她在外人眼里的名字
Or, as some know her,
卡拉·丹弗斯
Kara Danvers.
有一天  你可能必须跟她一模一样
One day, you may have to be just like her.
行动  思考都要一样
Move like her, think like her.
那么
So,
你看到了什么
what do you see?
她喜欢舒适
She likes comfort.
她没有自制力
She's undisciplined.
这些都是她的吗
All of this is for her?
她就像住在塔里的公主
She is like a princess in a tower.
靠着记者的工资生活
And on a reporter's salary.
有人来了
Someone is coming.
卡拉
Kara!
艾丽克斯
Alex.
我以为你在斯摩维尔
I thought you were in Smallville.
我明确记得你
I mean, I specifically remember you
让我照顾你那十亲九故呢
asking me to take care of your leafy dependents.
是的  斯摩维尔  我...
Yeah, yes. Uh, Smallville. Yeah, I, uh...
-我...  -你没取消
- I... - Oh, you didn't cancel
你的度假吧
your vacation, did you?
我跟你说过我会代管超查部
I told you that I would hold down the fort at the DEO.
但你没去
I mean, but you are missed.
不  当然了  我没取消我的度假
No. Of course, I didn't cancel my vacation.
我只是...  忘了我的日记
I... I just... I... I forgot my journal.
看看我
Look at me.
糊涂的撰稿人  没带她的日记
Silly writer, without her journal.
好吧  很好
Okay, well, good.
你应该...
Well, you should...
你应该去了  是吧
You should be going, right?
好的  我会的  谢谢你  艾丽克斯
Yeah, okay, okay, I will. Thank you, Alex.
拜拜
Bye.
-拜拜  -再见
- Bye. - See ya.
卡拉·丹弗斯也有个艾丽克斯吗
Kara Danvers has an Alex, too?
你们有很多共同点  但它们并不重要
You have a lot in common except for what counts.
实地考察结束了  我得回到
Field trip's over. I have to go back to--
-监狱里去  -是的
- To prison. - Yes.
回卡兹尼亚  确保没人看到你
Go back to Kaznia. Make sure you weren't seen.
不能有人知道你的存在
No one can know that you exist.
格兰特女士今天只威胁了我六次
Ms. Grant only threatened to fire me
说要开除我
six times today.
我觉得她越来越喜欢我了
I think she's warming to me.
莉娜不知道她有多大的潜力
Lena doesn't realize how much potential she has.
我希望现在至少全世界会知道
I hope now at least the world will.
莉娜·卢瑟
Lena Luthor.
卡拉
Kara!
你在这里干什么  我以为你去度假了
What are you doing here? I thought you were on vacation.
我...
I, uh...
我得帮艾丽克斯处理一些事情
I had to help Alex with something.
卢瑟女士
Ms. Luthor.
卢瑟女士  抱歉打断一下
Ms. Luthor. Sorry to interrupt.
C实验室需要你  这事很急
You're needed in Lab C, and it can't wait.
不好意思  你回了以后  办个女生之夜吧
I'm sorry, but when you get back, maybe a girl's night?
大肚腩汉堡
Big Belly Burger.
就像你去年的生日
Like your birthday, last year.
成交
Sold.
你好  "卡拉"
Hello, "Kara."
或者我该叫你  女贞
Or should I say, Privet?
艾丽克斯不可能派你来L公司
There is no way Alex sent you to L-Corp.
-你在这里干什么  -我想见他妹妹
- What are you doing here? - I wanted to meet his sister.
好了  你见过她了
Okay, well, you met her,
所以现在回你的套娃里去
so now get back to your nesting doll.
我还没准备好
I'm not ready.
美国是令人讨厌  但我不太确定
America is unsavory, but I'm not so sure
它有艾丽克斯认为的那么差
it is bad as Alex thinks--
不不不不
Oh, no. No, no, no.
你不会去吃所有的苹果派
You are not gonna go all apple pie-eating,
挥舞国旗  假装讨好我
flag-waving, Philip Jennings on me.
卡拉·丹弗斯想要做好事
Kara Danvers wants to do good.
她有同情心  她有很多朋友
She has compassion. She has friends.
莉娜就是其中一个
And Lena is one of them.
为什么
Why is that?
我们有麻烦了
We've got a problem.
你的小项目有她自己的想法
Your little project's got a mind of her own,
她要让你完全脱离
and she's about to star-spangle you
这个世界的控制
right out of world domination.
恐慌对你来说并不好  泰斯马克女士
Panic is a bad color on you, Ms. Tessmacher.
我能解决这个
I can fix this.
你和奥蒂斯得去卡兹尼亚
You and Otis will have to go to Kaznia.
什么  为什么
What? What for?
因为那是她最爱的地方
Because that's where the thing she loves most is.
如果美国人把它从她那里夺走了
And she's gonna be ever so sad when the Americans
她会很很伤心的
take it away from her.
孩子
Hey, kid.
你好  水手
Hey, sailor.
导弹锁定目标
Missile engaging target.
谁会这么做
Who would do this?
你已经知道了
You already know.
阿美特克  贪婪的美国人
AmerTek. The greedy Americans.
别这么做
Don't do this.
听我说  卢瑟家族在等待时机
Listen to me. Luthors bide their time.
这只是一个美国人...
This is just an American--
-拜托  停下  -不
- Please, stop. - No!
你可能破坏了我们所有的工作
You could have compromised all of our work.
-他们杀了米凯尔  -一条命是什么
- They killed Mikhail! - What is one life?
和世界比起来  一条命什么都不是
One life is nothing next to the world!
你赌进去一切  却不听我的话
You risked everything, and you did not listen to me!
你不能命令我
You don't give me commands.
我在帮你
I am helping you.
他们看到了你的脸
They saw your face.
如果你被认出来了  世界会追捕你
If you were identified, the world would hunt you down!
我会让这看起来像个意外
I'll make this look like an accident.
破坏  误杀  我来收拾你的烂摊子
Sabotage, friendly fire. I will clean up your mess!
你就是这么看我的吗
Is that what you think of me?
把我当宠物  专门收拾我的烂摊子
That I am some pet you clean up after?
当然不是
Of course not.
那是某个水手吗
Some soldier then?
亚历山大大帝的征服军
Alexander's conquering army!
我是什么
What am I?
我为什么在这里
Why am I here?
为什么卡拉·丹弗斯有个艾丽克斯
Why does Kara Danvers have an Alex?
她为什么和你妹妹是朋友
And why is she friends with your sister?
这就是问题所在
That's what this is about.
这和莉娜有关
This is about Lena.
我以为你变强了
I thought you were stronger.
但人们失望了
But people disappoint.
我完事了
I'm done here.
我死过一次
Oh, I died once.
所以我相信第二次机会
So I believe in second chances,
但如果你看见秃头男
but if you see a bald guy...
任何秃头男
Any bald guy.
你要躺在地上装死
You lie on the floor. You pretend you're dead.
好吗
Okay?
三个月前
什么
What?
哪种病
What kind of illness?
-莱克斯  -我们把她逼过头了
- Lex. - We pushed her too far.
或许是黑氪石引起了细胞无限制生长
Maybe the Black Kryptonite caused unchecked cell growth.
-那就是癌症了  -莱克斯
- That'd be cancer-symptomatic. - Lex.
也可能是端粒的问题
Could be a telomere problem.
我们必须要稳定住衰老
We need to stabilize the senescence--
-莱克斯  -什么
- Lex! - What?
对了
Oh, right.
哈伦·艾尔
The Harun-El.
是它创造了她
It made her.
或许也能稳定她  给我拿来
It might stabilize her. Bring it to me.
那个还没准备好
It's not ready yet.
莉娜的实验仍然是百分百的死亡率
Lena's trial still has a 100 percent mortality rate.
-那我来解决  -这个女孩要死了
- Then I'll solve it. - The girl is dying.
那你建议我怎么做
What do you suggest I do?
她是我的毕生心血  她就是个
She is everything I have worked for. She's a...
奇迹
A miracle.
天空开了个洞  把她送给了我
The skies opened up and gave her to me. I...
我不能失去她
I can't lose her.
我有个主意  但你是不会喜欢的
I have an idea, but you're not gonna like it.
-我们要  -你说对了
- What we-- - You're right.
我要让自己得癌症
I have to give myself cancer.
这不是我想说的
That is not what I was gonna say.
不  你会说  我需要和莉娜合作
No, you were going to tell me that I need to work with Lena.
你说得对  但是她不会同意
And you're right, except she won't buy it.
她绝不会和我合作
She'll never work with me,
但她会
but she will
救我
save me.
不  莱克斯  不
No, Lex. No!
妹妹
Hey, sis.
我讨厌你对这个地方做的变动
I hate what you've done with the place.
五周前
我就直说了
I'll be direct.
黑氪石
Black Kryptonite.
哈伦·艾尔
The Harun-El.
你手上都有  而我需要
You have it, and I need it.
你知道它不会让你生发
You know it doesn't grow back hair.
想象力别太贫瘠
Don't be pedestrian.
你是卢瑟家的一份子
You're a Luthor.
我似乎记得在那一点上意见有所不同
I seem to remember some disagreement on that point.
我没什么意见
Not from me.
你搬进来的第二天  我就擦洗了你的脸颊
I swabbed your cheek the day after you moved in.
我一直对我们的基因很感兴趣
I've always been interested in our genes.
优点  弱点
Strengths. Weaknesses.
酗酒
Alcoholism.
所以这就是你的计划
So that's your plan.
来谈我们酗酒的父亲
Come here to talk about our drunk father?
接下来呢  你会说你爱我吗
What's next? You tell me you love me?
爱情不值钱  我尊重你
Love is valueless. I respect you.
不  你不能这样
No. You don't get to do that.
你不能就这么走进来  想拿什么拿什么
You can't just come in here and take what you want.
莉娜  我是一个全息图
Lena, I'm a hologram.
我什么都拿不了
I can't take anything.
但我懂
But I get it.
你不想放弃你的研究
You don't wanna give up your research.
让你感到舒适
It's cozy,
让人沉迷其中
the comfort of obsession.
我不是你
I'm not like you.
我想帮助人类
I wanna help people.
我就是人类
I'm people.
你在用黑石制造超级士兵
And you're using the black rock to make super soldiers.
那是在帮谁
Who is that helping?
我花了点时间  想了想
I've had some time, done some thinking,
-关于重新做人  -那得是剧变
- some leaf-turning-over-- - It's a big leaf.
别走我的老路
Don't do what I did.
有能力救人就别害人
Don't harm when you could heal.
我才意识到你没问我要黑石干什么
Oh, I just realized you haven't asked me why I need the black rock.
我猜是自杀
I assumed homicide.
刚好相反
Just the opposite.
我要死了
I'm dying.
两天前
看着她
Take care of her.
卡兹尼亚
现今
一切就绪
Here goes everything.
艾丽克斯
Alex?
我以为你走了
I thought you were gone.
你让我非常非常生气
You made me very, very angry.
但我答应过
But I promised
不会再让你生病
that I wouldn't let you get sick again.
你救了我
You saved me.
我在你身上投入了很多
I had a lot invested in you.
我不应该就那样离开
And I shouldn't have left the way that I did.
这跟莉娜没关系
This is not about Lena.
这事关你我
This is about you and me.
你能原谅我吗
Can you forgive me?
超女
Supergirl
感情用事
acts on her emotions.
自私
It's selfish,
丑陋
ugly.
我不会成为她
I will not be her.
我就是我
I will be me.
我会遵守纪律
I will be disciplined.
我会服从于你
I will follow you
然后摧毁她
and destroy her.
你记得亚历山大大帝和他父亲的故事吗
Do you remember that story about Alexander the Great and his father?
我记得
I remember.
你以为我是亚历山大
You thought I was Alexander.
但我是菲利普
But I'm Philip.
我只有一次生命
I only get one lifetime.
但你是
But you're...
永恒的
forever.
我献给世界的礼物
My gift to the world,
我的遗产
my legacy.
我的血红之女
纳欣诺市
现今
出什么事了
What's wrong?
是莱克斯·卢瑟
It's Lex Luthor.
他逃了
He's free.
我试图阻止他  但他还是逃了
I tried to stop him, but he got away.
-什么  -莉娜
-What? - Lena.
她知道了吗
Does she know?
我不清楚
I don't know.
好吧  我会找到她
Okay, I will find her.
你叫上荣恩去找莱克斯
You get J'onn and find Lex.